<root>
    <blog1>
        <h1>Top 10 Benifits of Yoga for Your Health</h1>
        <author>Orthopaedic Hospital of Wisconsin</author>
        <date>08/04/2022</date>
        <desc>Yoga, a practice known for its health and relaxation benefits, has become an everyday exercise among all age groups. If you’ve never tried yoga, you may be intimidated by popular photos online of people practicing...</desc>
        <blogdata>Yoga, a practice known for its health and relaxation benefits, has become an everyday exercise among all age groups. If you’ve never tried yoga, you may be intimidated by popular photos online of people practicing acro yoga. However, most yoga practices offer health benefits for people at all stages of flexibility, athletic ability, and stamina. You might even be prescribed movements derived from yoga by your physical therapist as you recover from orthopedic surgery or treat an orthopedic condition.


At Orthopaedic Hospital of Wisconsin, we want you to feel your best and lead a healthy lifestyle. Part of this includes staying active and mobile. Whether you need a low-impact exercise recommended by your physical therapist or are just looking for a new exercise program, yoga can offer many worthwhile health perks. Below we describe the top 10 benefits that yoga can bring into your life.


Range of Motion in Joints.
If you struggle with moving certain areas of your body, yoga is a great way to improve your range of motion. Perhaps your hips are tight, or your shoulders don’t allow you to reach as far as you would like. Yoga pose staples, like a downward-facing dog, require you to exhibit an average or above average range of motion in the shoulders, hips, and ankles. If you can’t do the post correctly, yoga offers a great way to set a range of motion goal. You can begin by trying pose modifications and work your way up to the correct pose as your range of motion improves with each yoga practice.


Flexibility in Muscles
Similar to improving range of motion, yoga improves your muscle flexibility. As you hit different yoga poses, your muscles bend and stretch to achieve the proper form. Over time, you’ll be able to move your muscles more and more as they get used to the movements. Yoga poses target the flexibility of different muscle groups, so you can pick and choose what movements might be more beneficial for your body.


Balance
Many yoga poses focus on creating a stable base for your body and improving your balance. Many poses will focus on grounding firmly through your feet and legs. They also often focus on maintaining an active core and stabilizing your body to achieve various movements. This focus on grounding and stabilization will improve your balance over time which easily translates to simple, everyday balancing. Improving your balance benefits your orthopedic health as it allows you to coordinate your movements. Balancing helps you to move and decreases the chance of falling over and injuring yourself.</blogdata>
    </blog1>
    <blog2>
        <h1>A Teenage Love Story</h1>
        <author>Karlie Duke</author>
        <date>02/19/2017</date>
        <desc>Teenage love stories are often awkwardly, impossibly romantic. The kind you find in sitcoms, books and blockbuster movies. Think awkward teen falling in love with a vampire who is 100 years older than her. Best friends finally realizing they love each other and living happily ever after. Imagine Inside Out’s picture of an...</desc>
        <blogdata>Think about your favorite love stories…are they real? From movie scenes? Are they written by your favorite author?

Teenage love stories are often awkwardly, impossibly romantic. The kind you find in sitcoms, books and blockbuster movies. Think awkward teen falling in love with a vampire who is 100 years older than her. Best friends finally realizing they love each other and living happily ever after. Imagine Inside Out’s picture of an imaginary boyfriend claiming, “I would die for Riley.”

In the midst of awkward imperfection comes perfect romance. We don’t watch movies or read books that end with a horrible breakup and no happy conclusion. We enjoy love stories that end with hope for a better future and hope that we could also one day find a love like that – a love that reads a notebook full of their love story every day, the kind of love that changes the beast into a man, a love that can even survive carbon-freezing in a galaxy far, far away.

But why don’t we put the same emphasis on the kind of love that is hard and real? Sometimes love hurts, it disappoints, it is jealous, it is almost always messy. When we have a view of love that is only good and sweet and always smells good, it is easy to walk away when it gets hard. Why would we settle for a love that doesn’t always bring joy? There must be something wrong with this person if I don’t always find them cute and charming like in the movies…

We do a disservice to teenagers when we encourage them to settle on surface-level, easy love. Because that’s what it is!

True love, faithful love is the kind of love that sticks it out when it isn’t easy. The kind of love you really want will be hard and difficult, but it is so worth it! That is what I want teenagers to hear.

Don’t settle for love that only comes around when your makeup is done or your shirt is clean – fall in love with the person who still kisses you when you have morning breath and a hole in your shirt. Don’t look for a love that completes your world – find someone who will make you better for the worl</blogdata>
    </blog2>
    <blog3>
        <h1>How to Create Quality Time with Your Spouse</h1>
        <author>Darcie Fuqua</author>
        <date>05/03/2022</date>
        <desc>How is your marriage Life Going on?
Even if your answer is great, you know it takes a concerted effort, time, and prayer to keep your marriage strong, engaged, and healthy. Staying in love requires communication and sacrifice by....
</desc>
    <blogdata>How is your marriage?

Even if your answer is great, you know it takes a concerted effort, time, and prayer to keep your marriage strong, engaged, and healthy. Staying in love requires communication and sacrifice by both partners. Spending quality time together is one of the most important ways to keep your relationship flourishing. According to Gary Chapman's book, The 5 Love Languages, the love language of quality time is about communicating your love and affection by spending exclusive time together.


Few Tips
Making eye contact, actively listening, and being present are keys to making the most out of your time together. This undivided attention requires removing distractions such as phones and tablets. You might need to look the opposite way of the dirty dishes and file the mental to-do list for the time spent together.



Way of Life
Quality time together as a couple will look different depending on the season of your life. Right now, our living room floors have scattered tiny toys ready to impale your bare feet when you least expect it. Colorful drawings cover the refrigerator, and sippy cups and cereal bowls litter the counters. My husband and I are knee-deep in the season of parenting young children, which is rewarding yet exhausting. Of course, our alone time is limited and quickly interrupted. So we have to get creative and focus on quality, not quantity, time together.


Whatever season, or the number of years you've been married, spending quality time can take some planning, compromise, and a lot of grace, but it is vital to a lasting and loving relationship. Let's discover some ways to create quality time with your spouse.


Spend Time Together with the Kids
Have you heard the phrase, "the couple who plays together stays together"? According to the Merriam-Webster Dictionary, the definition of quality time is time spent giving all of one's attention to someone close. Typically, this equates to spending one-on-one time together, but this is not always an option when you have children. Incorporating the kids in the mix might not be the ideal form of spending quality time together, but it can be a great family-bonding experience for your whole gang


Spend Time Together in the Mundane
It doesn't take much to rearrange schedules and enjoy a cup of coffee with each other in the morning. There are many tasks and chores throughout the day where you can slip in a devoted 15 to 30 minutes in conversation.


Spend Time Together on a Date Night Out
One of my mentors, Dr. Bob, told me that a weekly date night is one of the keys to his fifty years of marriage. When he was a doctoral student, he was married and had a toddler. A professor brought him into his office and told him that he was the only married student and the only one with a child. The professor wanted him to graduate and stay married, so he assigned Dr. Bob an extra course. He would have to take his wife on a weekly date night, and they both couldn't talk about work, school, or their child. They also had to do things and have conversations that reminded them why they fell in love. They had to get creative with their dates because Dr. Bob was a poor college student at the time, and he paid his students to babysit with extra credit. They never missed a week during his program, and they kept the weekly night out tradition going through another child and two businesses. Dr. Bob will tell you it saved his marriage. Most of us with young kids can't get away for date night every week, but setting aside time and money for an occasional escape should be a priority.</blogdata>
    </blog3>
</root>